SRINIVASA KARTHIC PONGURU

Houston, TX | (832) 908-6965 | karthic.psa@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

Summary

A highly skilled and motivated Full-Stack Software Developer with the ability to visualize abstract algorithms and dynamic data structures. A non-linear thinker with a strong belief in Test Driven Development and a passion to build beautiful, responsive, cross-device compatible websites and web apps which create an immersive experience for the user.

Education

MASTER OF SCIENCE | UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON | HOUSTON, TEXAS

| MAY 2017 |

· Major: Computer and Systems Engineering | GPA: 3.78

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING | ANNA UNIVERSITY | CHENNNAI, INDIA

| MAY 2014 |

· Major: Computer Science and Engineering | GPA: 8.97

NANODEGREE | UDACITY

| DEC 2017 |

· Program: Full Stack Web Developer

Technical Skills

Languages : Python, Java, C#, C++, JavaScript (ES2015/ES2016), SQL, HTML5, CSS3
JavaScript Frameworks / Libraries : jQuery, Angular, D3.js, knockout.js, AJAX, Node.js, Backbone.js

Python Web Frameworks : Flask, Django, webapp2 Frontend Frameworks / Tools : Bootstrap3, Semantic-UI

Python Template Engine : Jinja2

Database Management Systems : MySQL, MS Access, PostgreSQL, SQL Server (2016/2012), Oracle (12c,11g)

Google Cloud Platform : App Engine, Cloud Datastore

JavaScript Task Runners : Grunt, Gulp Version Control : Git, SVN, TFS

Operating Systems : Windows, Linux (Ubuntu)

Experience

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | SLIDKA INC

| JUNE 2016 - PRESENT |

- · Developed a real-time application with Python and Django Framework where registered users can select or cancel a certain service from a list of services available within various departments and provides new users with a user registration and authentication system.
- Designed and implemented a reporting tool that summarizes required data by using Python and Flask with SQLAlchemy as an Object Relational Mapper (ORM) for querying the PostgreSQL database and to perform CRUD operations.
- · Worked in Agile-Scrum development methodology.
- Utilized Amazon LightSail for deploying Linux server instances using a virtual machine running Ubuntu 16.04.
- · Developed the UI for the website with HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, JavaScript, knockout.js and jQuery.
- Designed and developed Single Page Application (SPA) using knockout.js and worked with RESTful web services and APIs.
- · Used jQuery's AJAX methods to reduce page reloads and for transmitting JSON data objects between frontend views and controllers.
- · Used various JSON APIs to translate the JSON data into a Python dictionary.
- · Utilized automation tools (Grunt/Gulp) in development workflow saving the team 40 hours of work a month.
- · Worked with SQL Server databases in writing PL-SQL stored procedures, triggers, views, and cursors.
- · Responsible for creating the database in SQL Server and PostgreSQL using SQLAlchemy ORM.
- · Utilized OAuth and built third-party sign-in solutions into web applications using authentication and authorization services.
- · Used knockout.js to create models that represent data and controllers to handle events triggered by clients and send request to server.

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER (GA) | UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON

| SEP 2016 - MAY 2017 |

- Collaborated with a cross-functional technical team and professors in developing and maintaining web applications and web pages with separation of concerns by following the model-view-controller architecture using Django framework and AngularJS.
- · Developed back-end modules using Python.
- Utilized Vagrant for maintaining portable virtual software development environments and for deploying independent Linux servers with their own firewall configuration using a virtual machine running Ubuntu.

- · Dealt with writing front-end component code using HTML5/CSS3, Bootstrap 3, JavaScript, jQuery, and AngularJS.
- Designed and developed Single Page Application (SPA) using AngularJS and implemented Two-Way Data-binding in AngularJS to handle the automatic synchronization of data between the model and view components for application
- · Engineered data visualizations with D3 and custom AngularJS directives for professors to view grades.
- · Created and implemented SQL Queries, Stored procedures, Functions, Packages and Triggers in SQL Server 2012.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT | UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON

| MAR 2016 - SEP 2016 |

- · Involved in designing ER models and database schema for exam scheduling system to represent student and course information and developed the tables with required constraints, relations and normalization rules in SQL Server 2012.
- · Involved in building database Model, APIs and Views utilizing Python and developed frontend modules and implemented the presentation layer with HTML, AJAX, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and Backbone.js to build an interactive web based solution.
- · Refactored existing code with separation of concerns by utilizing the MV* (MVVM/MVC) organizational architecture.
- · Involved in developing back-end web applications & REST APIs.
- · Used jQuery's AJAX methods for transmitting JSON data objects and to reduce page reloads and load times
- · Set up rules and policies with a Node.js and developed the back-end modules with Python.
- · Utilized Git for version control.

WEB DEVELOPER | IIS TECHNOLOGIES | CHENNNAI, INDIA

| MAY 2014 - JUL 2015 |

- · Served as part of a high-performing agile web applications engineering team in the role of a web developer working with HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Enterprise Java and Python.
- · Conducted extensive site monitoring and testing utilizing developer tools; found and fixed the website problems such as broken links, typographical errors, and formatting inconsistencies.
- Helped in developing responsive, cross-device compatible websites which create an immersive experience for the user, using jQuery, JavaScript, AJAX and Bootstrap.
- Utilized jQuery and JavaScript to select HTML elements, manipulate the DOM and change a webpage dynamically.

Projects

DESIGN A TOURNAMENT RESULTS DATABASE

| APR 2017 - MAY 2017 |

- · Developed a database schema to store the game matches between players.
- · Wrote code to query this data and determine the winners of various games.

MULTI USER BLOG | MAR 2017 – APR 2017 |

- · Created a multi user blog for users to sign in and create blog posts, 'Like' and 'Comment' on other posts.
- · Developed back-end code with Python and engineered frontend UI with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery.
- · Hosted blog on Google App Engine and created an authentication system for users to sign in or register.

MOVE PLANNER APPLICATION

| MAR 2017 - APR 2017 |

- Developed a Move Planner web app that is fully responsive using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and the Bootstrap framework.
- The application uses the New York Times API and the Wikipedia API to give relevant information about a place you plan to move.
- The page reads content from a JSON file using jQuery's AJAX functions and dynamically displays it within a provided template.

MOVIE TRAILER WEBSITE

| FEB 2017 - MAR 2017 |

- · Wrote server-side code in Python to store a list of movies, including box art imagery and a movie trailer URL.
- The data was later served to a web page using HTML, CSS and JavaScript allowing visitors to watch different trailers.

Publication

HYBRID GENETIC ALGORITHM APPROACH FOR MOBILE ROBOT PATH PLANNING

| DEC 2014 |

Advances in Natural and Applied Sciences (ISSN: 1995-0772), 8(17) Special 2014